VINICIUS PESSOA DA SILVA

Location: Brazil, São Paulo | Contact: +55 (11) 983531371 | E-mail: vini.pessoa99@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/vinicius-pessoa/ | GitHub: https://github.com/Vini9-9

PROFILE

Application Developer with **3+ years** of IT experience with versatility in both **back-end** and **front-end** development. **Supportive team player dedicated** to resolving project issues. Ability and willingness to **innovate** and **learn new technologies** and passionate about the concept of **continuous improvement** that motivates me to **make a difference in my work**.

EXPERIENCE

11/2022 - 03/2023

IBM at Oi (Telecom industry)

Application developer

Processes improvement of current environment and incident handling of legacy code.

- Back-end development of microservices in **Node.JS** and **Java** with **Spring boot**.
- Test coverage (+80%) with Sonar.
- Maintenance of microservices with Jenkins, Azure and Openshift.
- Development queries in Oracle DB and MongoDB.
- Development of automation process in **repetitive tasks** in **Node.JS** and **VBA**.

08/2022 - 12/2023

IBM at Bradesco Seguros (Insurance industry)

Application developer (part time)

Design and implement of features to streamline routines.

- Back-end development of APIs in Node.JS
- Unit tests using Jest.
- Test coverage (+80%) with **Sonar**.
- Maintenance of microservices with Jenkins.

07/2022 - 11/2022

IBM at Digital Bank Next (10+ Million users)

Application developer

Design and implement of features to improve the experience of end user in updating customer data (social name, address, income).

- Back-end development of APIs in Java with **Spring boot**.
- Unit tests using JUnit and Mockito.
- Test coverage (+80%) with **Sonar**.
- Maintenance of microservices with **Azure** and **Bamboo**.
- Development queries in Oracle DB.

04/2022 - 07/2022

IBM at Internal projects

Full-stack developer (GBS associates)

Development of supervised projects.

I built **on my own** a **data management API** in **Java** with **Spring boot** with the following tasks performed:

- Spring data JPA to interact with MySQL.
- Authentication via web token with JWT.
- Segregated environments.
- Unit tests and integrated tests.
- · Swagger documentation.
- Environment setup with docker and docker compose.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science and Technology

UFABC (2018 – 2023)

&

Computer Science **UFABC** (2020 – 2024)

LANGUAGES

- Portuguese Native.
- Spanish Intermediate.

MAIN TECHNOLOGIES

- Java with Spring Boot;
- Node.JS in Typescript;
- React native in Typescript;
- Angular in Typescript;
- HTML, Java Script and CSS;
- Docker and docker compose;

Databases

 MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Oracle DB;

Tests

• Selenium, Junit, Jest, Mockito:

PROJECTS

- Time-clock control (Node.JS and React Native);
- Vacation planner (Node.JS);
- Data management API (Spring Boot);
- API inventory control for books (Node.JS);
- API Brazilian holidays (Node.JS);
- Web scraping (Node.js);
- Tasks automation (VBA);

I built on my own a time-clock control application in Typescript with **NodeJS** on back-end and **React Native** on front-end, with the following tasks performed:

- Elaboration of entity-relationship model (ERM).
- Backlog organization via Trello (**Kanban**).
- Design elaboration via Figma.
- Authentication via web token with JWT.
- TypeORM to interact with PostgreSQL.

05/2021 - 03/2022

IBM at Bradesco saúde (Health care industry)

Application developer

Modernization of systems connected to the referenced portal

- Front-end development with HTML, CSS, JS with Jquery.
- Back-end development with Struts on Java;
- · Consumption of APIs in JS;
- Automated tests with Selenium and Junit;

I HAVE BEEN STUDYING...

- AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner
- AWS Serverless APIs & Apps
- Azure Fundamentals: AZ-900 Certification
- Master Electron: Desktop Apps with HTML, JS & CSS
- Java Messaging Service Spring MVC, Spring Boot, ActiveMQ